Finding Aid for Religious Communities of Michigan Web Archive
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Religious Communities of Michigan Web Archive
2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library.
2014025 Aa 3 [2014038]
Web collection of websites created by various religious communities of the State of Michigan, archived by the Bentley Historical Library using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010.
30 web sites online; multiple captures
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Websites gathered beginning in 2010 using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service web crawler.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michigan's religious communities are among Bentley Historical Library's most important topical collections priorities. The topic's priority is based on the Bentley Library's mission as established by the University of Michigan Board of Regents to document "the state, its institutions, and its social, economic, and intellectual development," the historical collecting patterns of the library, and overall collection development priorities in all formats. The process of setting collecting priorities is described by Christine Weideman's "A New Map for Field Work: Impact of Collections Analysis on the Bentley Historical Library" (American Archivist, Winter 1991, Vol. 54 Issue 1, pp. 54-60.) and Judith E. Endelman's "Looking Backward to Plan for the Future: Collection Analysis for Manuscript Repositories." (American Archivist, Summer 1987, Vol. 50 Issue 3, pp. 340-355.)
In selecting web content for permanent preservation, the Bentley Historical Library seeks:
Websites of organizations or individuals whose archives the Library is committed to preserve.
Website that fill gaps in existing collections.
Websites with unique content that documents the work and/or thought process of a person or organization.
Websites that periodically incorporate new content or feature regular updates.
Websites with content that is not likely to be duplicated in an individual or organization's paper records.
As of 2013, the Bentley Library will concentrate efforts on documenting Michigan's religious institutions and leaders, with a focus on religious and spiritual lives of the State's diverse ethnic and cultural communities. In addition to these priorities, the MHC remains open to the consideration of material with great research potential in any area of Michigan's diverse religious history.
To learn more about the Bentley Historical Library's Web Archives visit http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/index.php.
The Web Archive of Michigan's Religious Communities collection contains archived websites created by various religious communities and institutions of the State of Michigan. The websites have been archived by the Bentley Historical Library, using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010. Access to all websites archived by the Bentley Historical Library is available at: http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/webarchives/index.php.
Web Archives include websites of churches, mosques, religious community centers and educational institutions who call the state of Michigan home. The collection is especially strong in documenting African American, Arab American, and Native American communities, business, religious, cultural and civil rights organizations, as well as distinguished individuals who belong to these communities.
The year that appears next to the website title in the contents list indicates the date that the website was first archived. Archived versions of the site from later dates may also be available.
Subjects:
Acton Institute for the Study of Religion and Liberty.; American Druze Society.; American Federation of Muslims of Indian Origin.; American Moslem Society.; Antiochian Basilica of St. Mary (Livonia, Mich.); Antiochian Orthodox Christian Archdiocese of North America.; Baker, Wayne E.; Begg, Victor.; Bell, Rob.; Catholic Church--Michigan--Ann Arbor.MichiganAnn Arbor.; Catholic Church--Michigan--Detroit.MichiganDetroit.; Chaldean American Ladies of Charity.; Council on American-Islamic Relations Michigan Chapter.; Council of Islamic Organizations in Michigan.; Dignity Detroit.; Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan.; Episcopal Church. Diocese of Michigan.--Periodicals.Periodicals.; Episcopal Church--Michigan--Periodicals.MichiganPeriodicals.; Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Michigan.; Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Michigan.; Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Michigan.; Greater Grace Temple (Detroit, Mich.); Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.); Islamic Center of America (Dearborn, Mich.); Mars Hill Bible Church (Grandville, Mich.); Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength (Detroit, Mich.); Michigan Muslim Community Council.; Muhammad, Warith Deen, 1933-2008.; Muslim American Logic Institute.; New Bethel Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.); NOOMA Spiritual Films.; Read the Spirit (Web site); Reconciliation Metropolitan Community Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Renewal Ministries (Organization); St. Mary Student Parish (Ann Arbor, Mich.); St. Matthew's & St. Joseph’s Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Sabbath the Sacrified Orthodox Monastery (Harper Woods, Mich.); St. Vladimir Orthodox Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Universal Fellowship of Metropolitan Community Churches--Michigan--Grand Rapids.MichiganGrand Rapids.; Universal Hagar's Spiritual Church.; University of Michigan--Religion.Religion.; University of Michigan. School of Business Administration--Faculty.Faculty.; Word Of Faith International Christian Center (Southfield, Mich.); African American churches--Michigan--Detroit.; African American churches--Michigan--Southfield.; African American Episcopalians--Michigan--Detroit.; African American Muslims--Michigan.; African American public worship--Michigan--Detroit.; African Americans--Michigan.; African Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; African Americans--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; African Americans--Religious life--Michigan--Southfield.; Anglican Communion--Michigan--Periodicals.; Arab Americans--Michigan.; Arab Americans--Michigan--Periodicals.; Arab Americans--Michigan--Livonia.; Baptists--Michigan--Detroit.; Bisexuals--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Catholic gays--Michigan--Detroit.; Catholics--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Chaldean Catholics--Michigan--Detroit.; Charities--Michigan--Detroit.; Christianity and other religions--Islam.; Christians--Michigan--Grandville.; Community centers--Michigan.; Druze women--Michigan.; Druzes--United States.; East Indian Americans--Michigan.; East Indian Americans--United States.; Economics--Religious aspects--Christianity.; Environmental justice--Michigan.; Episcopalians--Michigan--Periodicals.; Ethnic communities.; Ethnic relations--Michigan.; Faith.; Freemasonry--Michigan.; Gays--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Gays--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Gays--Religious life--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; GLBT community of Michigan.; Housing policy--Michigan--Religious aspects.; Hurley, George W. African-American churches--Michigan--Detroit.; Iraqis--Michigan--Detroit.; Islam--Michigan.; Islamic education--Michigan.; Lesbians--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Monasteries--Michigan--Harper Woods.; Mosques--Michigan.; Mosques as community centers--Michigan.; Muslims--India.; Muslims--Michigan.; Muslims--Michigan--Periodicals.; Muslims--Religious life--Michigan.; Orthodox Eastern monasteries--Michigan--Harper Woods.; Pentecostalism--Catholic Church.; Religion.; Religion--Miscellanea.; Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov' zagranitsei­; Sermons, American.--Michigan--Detroit.; Social ethics.; Social justice.; Transgender people--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Transportation and state--Michigan--Religious aspects.; Women--Charities.; Women in Michigan.; Alma (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.); Battle Creek (Mich.); Dearborn (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Race relations.; Flint (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.)--Religion.; Grandville (Mich.); Harper Woods (Mich.); India.; Jackson (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); Lansing (Mich.); Livonia (Mich.); Muskegon (Mich.); Saginaw (Mich.); Southfield (Mich.)
Contributors:
Muslim Observer.
Genre Terms:
Blogs.; Websites.
- Religious Communities of Michigan Web Archives
  - Acton Institute for the Study of Religion and Liberty, 2012
  - American Druze Society, 2011
  - American Federation of Muslims of Indian Origin, 2012
  - American Muslem Society, 2010
  - Antiochian Basilica of St. Mary, 2010
  - Chaldean American Ladies of Charity, 2010
  - Council on American-Islamic Relations Michigan, 2011
  - Dignity Detroit, 2012
  - Grand Lodge of Michigan (Alma, Mich.), 2011
  - Greater Grace Temple, 2011
  - Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - Islamic Center of America, 2011
  - Mars Hill Bible Church, 2011
  - Metropolitan Organizing Strategy Enabling Strength, 2012
  - Michigan Muslim Community Council, 2011
  - Muslim American Logic Institute, 2012
  - Muslim Observer, 2011
  - New Bethel Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - NOOMA Spiritual Film, 2011
  - Read the Spirit, 2012
  - Reconciliation Metropolitan Community Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.), 2012
  - Record: The Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, 2011
  - Renewal Ministries, 2011
  - Rob Bell, 2011
  - St. Mary Student Parish (Ann Arbor, Mich.), 2012
  - St. Matthew's & St. Joseph's Episcopal Church (Detroit, Mich.), 2011
  - St. Sabbath the Sacrified Orthodox Monastery (Harper Woods, Mich.), 2011
  - St. Vladimir Orthodox Church (Dexter, Mich.), 2011
  - Universal Hagar's Spiritual Church--George H. Latimer-Knight Ministries International, 2011
  - World of Faith International Christian Center (Southfield, Mich.), 2011